Cell division is required for an organism生物体 to grow, mature, and maintain tissues.
During the mitotic phase, a cell will undergo mitosis to form two new nuclei细胞核核
and then divide to form two new individual cells during cytokinesis原浆移动.
Mitosis is the process of dividing the duplicated DNA of a cell into two new nuclei核.
Mitosis is split into distinct stages.
The first stage is prophase早期;
the DNA condenses浓缩, organizes, and the classic chromosome染色体 structure appears.
Next comes prometaphase前中期 where microtubules微管 attach to the chromosomes.
This step is followed by metaphase中期 where the chromosomes align.
Metaphase is followed by anaphase后期 where the chromosomes separate分离.
Finally, during telophase有丝分裂末期 nuclear membranes核膜 reappear around the two sets of chromosomes染色体.
Mitosis is now complete.
After mitosis two new cells are formed by a process called cytokinesis原浆移动.
Mitosis is only one part of what is called the cell cycle.
For many eukaryotic真核 cells, a cell is duplicated every 24 hours.
Most of the life of a cell is spent in interphase细胞分裂间期.
Interphase consists of three stages called
G1, S, and G2.
G1 (or Gap 1) is the first growth stage of interphase.
In G1, the cell grows to nearly its full size
and performs many of its specific biochemical functions that aid the organism有机体.
Next is the S (or synthesis合成) phase.
This is an important stage, because it is during the S phase
that DNA in the nucleus细胞核 is replicated复制.
The cell next enters another growth stage called G2 (or Gap 2).
It is during G2 that the cell finishes growing.
Once the cell has duplicated DNA in the nucleus,
and two centrosomes中心体 have appeared in the cytoplasm细胞质,
mitosis can begin.
For a typical eukaryotic真核 cell this will last about 80 minutes.
During the first stage of mitosis, called prophase前期,
we first see the classic chromosome structure.
This occurs through a condensation聚合 process.
At the same time, protein strands蛋白质链 called microtubules微管
appear from the centrosomes中心体 in animals.
Finally, a structure found within the nucleus, the nucleolus核仁, disappears.
Next, prometaphase前中期 begins when the nuclear membrane核膜 is broken down.
At the same time, microtubule strands, or spindle fibers纺锤丝,
are growing from the centrosomes.
These strands attach to a protein structure called the kinetochore着丝粒.
One kinetochore is attached to the centromere of each sister chromatid染色单体.
Next comes metaphase中期.
During this stage the sister chromatids染色单体 align along the center of the cell
so that both chromatids face toward opposite poles极 of the cell.
Now the sister chromatids are ready to be separated.
This occurs during anaphase后期
through a shortening of the microtubules attached to the kinetochores动粒.
Additionally, the poles of the cell move farther apart
and cause increased separation of sister chromatids.
At the end of anaphase, the sister chromatids have moved to the two ends of the cell.
Telophase末期 is the final stage of mitosis.
It is here the components of the new cells begin to appear.
At this point the spindle fibers纺锤丝 are broken up.
A new nuclear membrane surrounds the chromosomes染色体 at the end of each cell.
And the chromosomes uncoil展开 and return to an uncondensed未伸展 state.
Mitosis is now complete.
The formation of two cells is all that remains.
Following mitosis, the cell undergoes a process called cytokinesis原浆移动.
First the cell is compressed by a contractile ring可收缩环 that divides the cell in nearly equal halves.
By now the organelles细胞器 in the cell have been replicated,
and are now divided between the two halves of the cell.
This includes mitochondria线粒体, golgi bodies高尔基体, and the rough ER.
Plant cells also have chloroplasts叶绿体.
Once split, the two new cells are now fully in the G1 stage of interphase分裂间期
and ready again to begin their growth.
Let’s watch the process one more time.
Mitosis begins with prophase.
Notice the DNA condensing into chromosomes during this stage.
Microtubules appear during prometaphase, and the nuclear membrane breaks down.
Metaphase occurs when the chromosomes are aligned at the center of the cell.
During anaphase the chromosomes are moving apart.
The telophase stage is marked by the appearance of new nuclear membranes.
This is the end of mitosis.
Finally, the splitting of the cell occurs during cytokinesis.
The two new cells are now ready to grow and perform their specialized functions.